Cheon Moo-yeong?
千無影？
-Is it really you? -Yes, it's me.
-真的是你嗎？ -是我沒錯
-How are you-- -Alive?
-你怎麼會… -還活著？
Cut the crap. Moo-yeong is dead. I saw it with my own eyes.
少來了，無影死了，我親眼看到的
Who exactly are you?
你究竟是誰？
It's me.
是我啊
Your friend, Moo-yeong.
你的朋友無影
This is proof that the three of us are one.
這是我們三人同心的證據
Whoever betrays this pact dies at my hands.
違背約定的人會死在我手上
What if I lose it?
如果我弄丟它怎麼辦？
I'll feed you deer poop.
那我會餵你吃鹿屎
-Deer poop, deer poop, deer poop-- -Hey!
-鹿屎… -喂！
How do you have that?
你怎麼會有這東西？
Because I don't want to eat deer poop.
因為我不想吃鹿屎啊
-No way. -I missed you.
-不可能 -我好想你
Are you red-white mask?
你是紅白面具人？
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
You haven't changed at all. You and your temper.
你和你的火爆脾氣，真的一點都沒變
Who are you?
你是誰？
The Governor-General has me as a target.
總督已經盯上我了
I won't be able to hide my identity for much longer.
我的身份隱瞞不了太久了
Please punish me! My brother did this because of me--
請閣長罰我吧！ 哥哥是因為我才做出這種事…
No, I put you in danger, ma'am.
不，是我害閣長身陷險境的
Don't cry.
不要哭
A gisaeng must become not a flower, but a weed in times like this.
妓生千萬不要在這種時候做花朵 要做一株野草
Don't let the pesticides phase you.
不要被殺蟲劑影響到
I promise I will.
我一定會做到的
Jae Yoo, keep an eye on the Governor-General.
載宇，監視總督的舉動
And…
還有
Don't get hurt.
不要受傷
Yes, ma'am. I'll do as you say.
是，我會聽從閣長的吩咐
What will happen to Myoyeongak now?
妙緣閣接下來要怎麼辦？
Run the business as if nothing happened.
若無其事地營業就好
I will protect Myoyeongak.
我會保護妙緣閣的
Madame, you'd better come outside.
閣長，您最好出來一下
What the hell are you two doing?
你們兩個在做什麼？
Please stop.
拜託你們別打了
What kind of fool do you two take me for?
你們兩個把我當成傻瓜嗎？
Ryu Hong-joo.
柳紅朱
Are you insane?
妳瘋了嗎？
You better not do that.
你最好不要拔劍
-You've been struck on a vital point. -By a mountain god's sword, at that.
-你被刺中要害了 -而且是被山神的劍
What are you trying to do?
妳想做什麼？
There are two of you.
總共有兩個李硯
And the opium addict in Manchuria is the real one.
在滿洲吸鴉片的癮君子才是真的
Damn, you caught me.
該死，被妳發現了
But…
但是
-I'm the real Lee Yeon too. -Except, you don't belong in this era.
-我也是真正的李硯 -只是不屬於這個時代
He lost a lot of blood.
他失血好多
I wonder how you ever came back?
我很好奇你是如何復活的？
Taluipa never revives those she kills, since she's all about principles.
奪衣婆絕對不會讓她處死的人復活 因為她奉行原則至上
I'm looking for answers too. As to who awakened me.
我也在尋找答案，是誰讓我復活
As to what I am, if I'm neither living nor dead.
我究竟是什麼，是生還是死
What happened on the day the four mountain gods were chosen?
四大山神選拔當天發生了什麼？
Tell me! What the hell did you do to ruin our friendship?
告訴我！你們究竟做了什麼 以至於毀掉了我們之間的友誼？
I killed…
我殺了…
Moo-yeong's older brother.
無影的哥哥
That's insane.
瘋子
But…
但是…
I don't regret doing it.
我不後悔那麼做
Shut your mouth.
閉嘴
I can't die here.
我不能死在這裡
I must go back.
我必須回去
-He's out of breath. -What will it be?
-他已經喘不過氣了 -怎麼辦？
The only one who can save him…
唯一可以救他的人
is you.
就是你
EPISODE 6
（第 6 集）
I think they're closed. Shall we go somewhere else?
好像打烊了，我們要不要換一家吃？
No. I eat where I want to eat.
不要，我想吃哪家就吃哪家
Bring me two bowls of naengmyeon.
給我上兩碗冷麵
We're closed. No more customers.
我們打烊了，不能接待顧客了
I want naengmyeon.
我要冷麵
You're full eating like that?
妳這樣也能吃飽嗎？
I'm full.
吃飽了
Men like mysterious women.
男人喜歡神祕的女人
Women who eat as little as birds
小鳥胃的女人
and don't even go to the toilet.
和不去洗手間的女人
Why? Is there something on my face?
怎麼了？我臉上有東西嗎？
You're a curiosity.
妳這樣的人很少見耶
I am?
是嗎？
A sales girl who turns out to be a mermaid in disguise.
偽裝成售貨員的人魚
A half-blood with weak legs who's really a master of destruction.
半人半魚，雙腿無力 實際上卻是一個破壞王
-Master of destruction? -You destroy all with your singing.
-破壞王？ -妳可以用歌聲摧毀一切
Did you inherit your voice from your mother?
這種聲音是從妳媽媽那裡繼承的嗎？
I hate my voice.
我討厭我的聲音
I only sing to make people happy.
我唱歌只是為了令人快樂
But I do that sometimes.
但我有時會造成破壞
Quit complaining. That's a blessing.
不要抱怨啦，這是妳的福分
You have the power to fight the world and protect yourself.
妳擁有對抗世界、保護自己的力量
Is that so?
真的嗎？
Then I will protect you.
那我願意保護你
Why would you protect me?
為什麼要保護我？
Because you still have five more wishes to grant me.
因為你還要幫我實現五個願望呢
Quite the woman of tenacity, huh?
還真是一個不肯退讓的女人啊
Check, please.
店主，結帳
-Go home. -You're not dropping me off?
-回家吧 -你不送我回去嗎？
-Would that be another wish? -No. I'll use it sparingly.
-這也是一個願望嗎？ -不，我要留著機會慢慢用
-Good night. -Yeah.
-晚安 -嗯
The one who did this to you…
是那隻九尾狐
is that nine-tailed fox?
把你傷成這樣的？
Yes, sir.
是
It could disguise itself. The Madame of Myoyeongak is one of them!
他會變幻人形 妙緣閣的閣長也是其中之一！
We must get rid of them now!
我們必須立即剷除他們！
Lee Yeon.
李硯
How wonderful.
真好啊
Joseon seems to be filled with utilizable demons.
朝鮮似乎到處都是可以利用的妖怪
Expedite the work at the gold mines.
加快金礦的開採工作
Give them the orders.
把命令傳下去
You will do nothing about Myoyeongak?
總督不打算對付妙緣閣嗎？
We are in the middle of war. Military expansion takes priority.
現在是戰爭時期 軍備擴張才是重中之重
As for us, we're going to the laboratory.
我們還是去實驗室吧
We have secured new Joseon demons to be our prey.
我們有抓到新的朝鮮妖怪充當獵物
No!
不對！
They are not prey.
他們不是獵物
They are new war weapons for the Empire!
是大日本帝國的新型作戰武器！
Yes, sir.
是
Did you find anything?
有什麼發現嗎？
-They won't be raiding Myoyeongak yet. -And the Chief Commissioner?
-他們暫時不會突襲妙緣閣 -首席專員呢？
I hear he's going to some laboratory with his right-hand man.
我聽說他帶副手去什麼實驗室了
-A laboratory? What's that? -Well…
-實驗室？那是什麼？ -那個…
It's top secret, so I don't know much.
這是最高機密，所以我知道的也不多
But there's a rumor that the hostages there aren't human.
但是有傳聞說那裡的人質不是人類
You're here.
妳來了
Let me introduce you to our newest member.
我來介紹一下我們的新成員
Whoa! These are your other members?
哇！這就是你們小組的其他成員嗎？
Let's see the goods from Manchuria first.
先來看看滿洲運來的貨物吧
This is what I picked up from Gyeongseong Station?
這是我從京城站拿回來的東西嗎？
-A real bomb? -I'm sure you know.
-是真正的炸彈嗎？ -你們一定知道
Both importing and carrying bombs is a serious crime.
進口和攜帶炸彈都是重罪
So from now on, we must protect each other.
從現在起，我們必須保護彼此
Even if we get exposed, I will claim that I did everything alone.
即便身份暴露 我也會獨自攬下所有罪名
-Me too. -Same here.
-我也會
And we are the Independence Volunteer Corps.
我們是獨立志願軍
When's the date?
日子定了嗎？
We will receive an order from Manchuria soon.
滿洲那邊很快會下命令的
Excuse me for a moment.
失陪一下
-Why are you here, sir? -I'm the keeper of the Stream of the Dead.
-大人為什麼在這裡？ -我是三途川的守門人
I've witnessed infinite deaths, but this has gone too far.
目睹過數不盡的死亡 但是這次太過分了
War, torture, and even forced labor. These lives don't deserve such a fate.
戰爭、酷刑，甚至是強迫勞動 這些生命不該承受這樣的命運
Does Taluipa know about this?
奪衣婆知道嗎？
She'd go berserk. Not to get involved in human affairs.
她會氣瘋的，不能插手人間事務嘛
It's a secret.
這是祕密
Well, Lord Lee Yeon doesn't know I'm here either.
李硯大人也不知道我在這裡
It's good to have you.
有你在真好
We are Joseon demons, after all.
畢竟我們是朝鮮妖怪
We can't have our country taken on our watch, no?
不能眼睜睜看著 祖國被霸佔，對不對？
You all are admirable, comrades.
同志們，你們都是可敬的人
Still have your talents, huh?
你的天賦還在啊？
He'll be up in half a day.
再過半天，他就可以下床了
Why are you saving him?
你為什麼要救他？
You said you died because of him, no?
你不是說你是被他害死的嗎？
I brought Yeon to the past to restore everything…
我把阿硯帶回過去是為了把一切
-to its rightful place. -"Rightful place"?
-恢復到應有的樣子 -“應有的樣子”？
Both my family and the forest I ruled.
無論是我的家人 還是我統治過的森林生靈
I intend to get them all back.
我都要他們活過來
And to do so, I need him.
想要做到這一點，我就需要他
Because this one has something that the one from this era doesn't.
因為他擁有 這個時代的阿硯沒有的東西
And what's that?
是什麼？
You'll find out soon.
妳很快就知道了
Does he know you're red-white mask?
他知不知道你是紅白面具人？
Shush.
噓
-Yeon, I'm scared. -A starving demon lives in this forest.
-阿硯，我害怕 -這林子裡住著一個飢腸轆轆的妖怪
The creature that feeds on humans and animals, regardless!
見到人類和動物都會統統吃掉
-Hey, stop tormenting him. -Fine.
-不要折磨他啦 -好吧
-Taluipa should know we're gone by now. -Let's go back now.
-奪衣婆應該發現我們逃走了吧 -我們現在回去吧
If we decided to run, we must see it to the end.
既然決定逃跑，就要堅持到最後
Just show me everything you have.
給我看看你們帶來的東西
You here to open a tavern or something?
紅朱，妳是來開小酒館的嗎？
I can't stand being hungry.
我受不了餓肚子的感覺
What's that?
那是什麼？
-I should still study, you know. -Geez, Cheon Moo-yeong.
-功課不能落下的 -天哪，千無影
You brought underwear?
你還帶了內衣？
I must have clean underwear, no matter what.
無論如何，我都要有乾淨的內衣
Oh, and this.
對了
Ta-da!
看！
-Isn't that Taluipa's favorite comb? -It's revenge for tormenting us.
-這不是奪衣婆最喜歡的梳子嗎？ -這是對她折磨我們的報復
This is proof that the three of us are one.
這是我們三人同心的證據
Whoever betrays this pact dies at my hands.
違背約定的人會死在我手上
What if I lose it?
如果我弄丟它怎麼辦？
I'll feed you deer poop.
那我會餵你吃鹿屎
-Deer poop, deer poop, deer poop-- -Hey!
-鹿屎… -喂！
I'm sorry, Yeon.
對不起，阿硯
To be honest,
老實講
I don't care if you're from the past or future.
我不在乎你來自過去還是未來
I'm going to protect you.
我會用我自己的方式
And Moo-yeong.
保護你
In my own way.
還有無影
Even if we end up in shreds.
即便我們最終化為碎片
We're hiring new gisaengs?
我們在招聘新的妓生嗎？
At a time like this?
在這種時候還招人？
Myoyeongak is open until Madame Ryu says otherwise.
妙緣閣要繼續營業 除非柳閣長另有吩咐
Gosh.
天哪
-How many are there? -We have six candidates.
-一共有幾位？ -有六位候選人
Madame will decide after she sees them.
閣長將在看到她們之後 決定她們的去留
How old? Are they pretty?
年齡呢？漂亮嗎？
She sure does hate the pretty ones, except for Madame Ryu.
她很討厭漂亮的女人，柳閣長除外
Shut it. You're not one of them.
閉嘴吧，反正妳也不漂亮
-You! Stand guard and report back to me. -Yes, miss.
-妳出去放哨，回來向我匯報 -是
-What is this? -It's a kind of invitation.
-這是什麼？ -一種邀請
Place this in an inconspicuous place, and it'll come to you.
把它放在一個不起眼的地方 牠便會來找你的
-If you want your body fixed, catch it. -"It"?
-如果你想修復身體，就要抓住牠 -“牠”？
That thing is-- Gosh, I'm sure being kind.
那個東西…天哪，我太善良了
Come closer.
靠過來
-How can something like that? -Forget it, then.
-怎麼會有那樣的東西？ -那還給我好了
-Never mind, sir. -But can you even catch it in that state?
-就當我沒問吧 -但你現在的狀態能抓到牠嗎？
It doesn't have to be me that catches it, no?
不一定非要是我親手抓，對不對？
A guest is coming.
有一位客人要來了
Yeon, this is a game fraught with danger.
阿硯，這是一場充滿危險的遊戲
So, please be my pawn.
所以，做我的棋子吧
Wow, so pretty.
天哪，好漂亮
How strange.
奇怪
How come there are seven, and not six?
為什麼是七位，不是六位嗎？
Honey?
老婆？
-The ice melts in my mouth like snow. -That's right!
-冰像雪花一樣入口即化 -沒錯！
This is what they call bingsu. It's big in Gyeongseong nowadays!
他們把它稱為冰酥 如今在京城超級爆紅！
You went out to eat this every night?
你每天晚上出門就是去吃這個嗎？
I mean, the lines are extremely long--
畢竟排隊的人超級多…
Since when did they sell bingsu at a boutique?
洋品店什麼時候開始賣冰酥了？
Whatever schemes you're a part of, you better do it in moderation.
無論你參與了什麼陰謀，適可而止吧
Humans write their history. Not us.
人類要自己書寫歷史，我們不能代勞
But we're the gods of Joseon--
可我們是朝鮮神靈…
Was there ever a death without a story?
史上哪一起死亡背後沒有故事？
Joseon survived amidst all those foreign invasions.
朝鮮撐過了那麼多次外敵入侵
They'll survive this too.
這次也能撐過去
Damn it! Those pricks are back?
該死！這些混帳又來了？
Gosh, those darn petty gods!
哎呀，這些可惡的小神！
This was our home for thousands of years!
幾千年來，這裡都是我們的家！
-I'll let them have it! -Off with those foreigners!
-我去教訓他們！ -趕走那些外來者！
You're all dead meat!
你們全部死定了！
TALUIPA MUST BE ENLIGHTENED!
（奪衣婆必須開明！）
Off with Taluipa for turning a blind eye to the indigenous gods!
對本土神靈 視而不見的奪衣婆滾出去！
Off with Taluipa! Off with Taluipa!
奪衣婆滾出去！
Sheesh.
哎呀
TALUIPA MUST BE ENLIGHTENED!
（奪衣婆必須開明！）
Why those little…
這些傢伙…
Sir, please let us meet Taluipa!
大人，讓我們見見奪衣婆吧！
Do you not know her temper?
你還不知道她的脾氣嗎？
-You'll be punished for this! -Damn it!
-你這樣會受罰的！ -該死！
-If I get punished, I'll get punished! -It's the outsiders.
-受罰就受罰！ -是那些外來者
They're butchering our forests, and destroying our totem poles!
他們正在屠殺我們森林的生靈 摧毀我們的圖騰柱！
So many gods are lost out there. We don't know if they're dead or alive!
很多神靈下落不明，生死未卜
You poor things.
你們太可憐了吧
Huh?
啊？
-You awake, babe? -Huh?
-親愛的，你醒了？ -啊？
You pierce me like a skewer, and you're calling me "babe"?
妳像做烤串一樣刺穿我 還有臉叫我“親愛的”？
-You're the one who used me all along. -"Used" you?
-是你一直在利用我嘛 -“利用”妳？
You sure played hard to get for a fake.
你這個冒牌貨很會玩欲擒故縱的遊戲
You're all the same underneath.
但是表象之下，你們都是一樣的
Oh, shit!
該死！
-What'd you do while I was asleep, huh? -Someone did do something…
-我睡著的時候，妳做了什麼？ -確實有人做過什麼
But it wasn't me.
但那不是我
No way.
不可能
He really is Moo-yeong, huh?
他真的是無影？
He really came back to life.
他真的復活了
I remember hearing a rumor.
我記得一個傳聞
That you passed the mountain god exam without striking a single demon!
你通過山神考核的時候 一個妖怪都沒打
You just treated them? Why?
你只是治好了他們？為什麼？
Well, to get in the easy way?
為了走捷徑
My gosh. "Get in easy"?
天哪，“走捷徑”？
His blood is as rare as they come. Once every hundreds of years.
他的血是數百年一見的珍寶
Draw some of it for me before you go. Or you can just sell it to me.
臨走之前抽一些血給我吧 賣給我也可以
-For how much? -At a bargain for being Yeon's buddy?
-你出多少錢？ -你是阿硯的朋友，便宜點好嗎？
Wow.
天哪
You sure are a dead ringer for him.
你跟他簡直一模一樣
We look nothing alike. Apologize.
我和他一點都不像，快道歉
Oh, Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人！
Are you okay now?
你沒事了吧？
Let's talk.
我們談談吧
Still can't believe it?
還是不敢相信嗎？
No, I believe that you are Moo-yeong.
不，我相信你是無影
But I need to know one thing.
但我必須問清楚一件事
Why did you come see me at this time?
你為什麼來這個時代見我？
And how did you find me?
你是如何找到我的？
Why do you think?
你說呢？
Well.
嗯
For this?
為了這個？
What's that?
那是什麼？
I thought you might know better than me.
我以為你比我更清楚
Now that makes me want to have it.
聽你這樣講，我反而想要得到它了
Just kidding. I don't need this stuff.
逗你玩的，我不需要這東西
How did you find me?
你是如何找到我的？
Half of my body…
我的半邊身體
is still no different from stone.
依然和石柱沒有區別
I don't know who revived me, but Taluipa's curse is still with me.
我不知道是誰讓我復活的 但是奪衣婆的詛咒沒有消失
I went looking for a cure at the pawnshop for demons.
我去妖怪當鋪尋找解藥
That's when I met them.
遇到了這個組織
VICTIMS' CLUB FOR DEMONS VICTIMIZED BY THE FOX
（被這隻狐狸傷害的 妖怪受害者俱樂部）
The raccoon couple? Were those pricks released?
浣熊夫婦嗎？ 那兩個混帳被放出來了？
I heard about you from them, and came straight here.
我從他們那裡聽說了你的事 直接趕到了這裡
You are welcome, friend.
歡迎你，朋友
Why don't you go visit the old hag? Ask her to return your body to normal.
為什麼不去找老妖婆呢？ 請她幫你的身體恢復正常
She'll never forgive me.
她永遠不會原諒我的
The mountain god who annihilated the forest he ruled.
我這個管轄森林的山神 毀掉了林中所有的生靈
-Why did you do it? -To save my brother.
-你為什麼那樣做？ -為了救我哥哥
Even if it cost me everything I cared for.
即便犧牲我曾經在乎的一切 也在所不惜
Looking good, you two.
你們兩個氣色不錯
Go change into something nice.
去換上好看的衣服吧
-What for? -Let's play, the three of us.
-為什麼？ -我們三個一起玩
Just like our carefree old days.
像無憂無慮的從前一樣
Excuse me. Didn't you stab us yesterday?
不好意思，妳昨天剛剛刺傷我們吧？
Just do as I say.
照我說的辦
We leave in an hour.
我們一小時後出發
Will you come…
你會不會來…
Become a star and fill this night
變成一顆星星照亮黑夜
How did you do that? You never learned the piano, no?
你是怎麼做到的？ 你沒有學過彈鋼琴吧？
I don't know. I just pressed what I heard.
我也不知道 我只是把聽到的音調彈出來
Rang, I think you might be a genius!
阿朗，你可能是個天才啊！
Well, they did say I was a fast learner ever since I was little.
在我小時候 他們的確有誇我學習能力強
-So cute. -I'm the boss of a bandit gang.
-真可愛 -我是土匪幫的頭目
Wishes or not. I can quit, you know.
許願什麼的，我可以爽約
Let's keep going.
我們繼續吧
You know this song.
你知道這首歌的
Someone there?
有人在那邊嗎？
Who's there?
是誰呀？
Gosh, you scared me!
天哪，妳嚇我一跳！
-The cook said the paste tastes strange. -Which paste?
-廚子說醬的味道怪怪的 -哪種醬？
Soybean, red pepper and soy. So all of them.
豆醬、辣椒醬、大醬，全都很奇怪
-Disgusting! -Yuck, huh?
-好噁心！ -噁心？
It is true. It tastes different, like it's gone bad.
真的耶，味道不一樣了，像是變質了
They say pastes change taste if trouble occurs in the house.
據說醬味變化是家中凶兆
Don't say such things.
不要講這種不吉利的話
-Did it get cursed in the making? -But we picked a lucky day.
-難道在製作過程中被诅咒了？ -但是我們選了吉日啊
PASTE WAS MADE ON A 'LUCKY DAY' WITH CURSE PREVENTION RITUALS
（做醬要選擇吉日 同時舉辦避邪儀式）
-We had a proper ritual too. -Then, what happened?
-儀式也照辦了 -那是怎麼回事？
Is someone there?
裡面有人嗎？
Have you seen my ring?
妳有沒有看到我的戒指？
Azulea? You lost your ring?
金花？妳的戒指丟了嗎？
But how did you get under there?
可是妳是怎麼鑽進去的？
Can you help me look for it? It's special to me.
妳可以幫我找一下嗎？ 它對我而言有特殊的意義
-Is this it? -Let me see.
-是這個嗎？ -給我看看
Just a little closer. Closer!
靠近一點，再近一點！
-Apricot! Azulea is-- -What about me?
-杏子！金花… -我怎麼了？
Weren't you just below the floorboard?
妳不是在地板下面嗎？
What are you talking about?
胡說什麼啊？
Oh, dear. You seeing delusions in broad daylight?
天哪，大白天就眼花了嗎？
Thank you.
謝謝
Let's go.
走吧
Here he goes again.
他又開始了
Okay, I'll go. I'll go.
好了，我自己走
I mean, why dress up to watch a darn movie.
為什麼要專門打扮來看該死的電影啊
What the hell!
搞什麼！
Why?
幹嘛不給我？
Will you guys be quiet?
你們安靜點好不好？
You should've just given them!
妳早點給我就沒事了！
-Are you crying? -Don't start.
-你在哭嗎？ -別惹他
You don't need to know.
你們不需要知道
-What? What the-- -It's raining!
-怎麼回事？搞什麼… -下雨了！
-Why is it suddenly raining? Damn it! -Hey!
-怎麼突然下雨了？該死！ -喂！
He gets so serious when he runs.
他跑起來就什麼都不管了
Well, he hates getting his fur wet.
他討厭弄濕皮毛
How was it? Seeing Yeon with your mask off?
怎麼樣？ 摘掉面具和阿硯見面的感覺如何？
He's still honest and wise, yet filled with confidence.
他依然誠實聰明又不可一世
All the things I liked about him.
都是我從前喜歡他的原因
-It's starting to rain heavily. -Hey!
-雨下大了 -喂！
Let's share it. I don't want you getting rained on.
一起披吧，我不想讓你淋雨
Then your other arm will get wet.
那妳的另一隻手臂會濕掉的
You haven't changed at all.
你一點都沒變
Damn it! Hey, give me that!
可惡！快給我！
-Hey, Lee Yeon! -Hey, come closer. Come, come.
-李硯！ -靠近點，快來
We should share, even if we all get a little wet.
即便每個人都淋濕一點也要分享嘛
He hasn't changed either.
他也沒有變
"Both Cheol-su's and Yeong-hui's house is 10km away from the bakery.
“哲秀家和永惠家 距離麵包店都是十公里
Cheol-su walked 5km per hour,
哲秀每小時走五公里
and Yeong-hui walked 3km per hour to the bakery.
永惠每小時走三公里去麵包店
When should they each leave their house if they were to meet at 2 p.m."
如果他們約在下午兩點在那裡見面 他們分別應該在什麼時間出門呢？”
Let's go over what we learned previously.
我們複習一下之前學過的內容
What're they eating? If it's gomboppang, I'm not going.
他們要去吃什麼？ 如果是奶油菠蘿包，我就不去了
-It's castella. -Gosh, I can't pass up on castella.
-是長崎蛋糕 -天哪，我不能放棄長崎蛋糕
Is Cheol-su handsome?
哲秀長得英俊嗎？
He's young, handsome, owns a car, and a cultural house.
年輕英俊、有一台車 還有一家文化館
Then, I can't go at 2 p.m. I have to stop by the hair salon.
那我不能下午兩點出發 我要先去美髮沙龍
Is there anyone who solved the problem?
有人解出這道題嗎？
Cheol-su needs to leave at 12 p.m. and Yeong-hui at 10:40 a.m.
哲秀要十二點出發 永惠要十點四十出發
-Correct! -What?
-正確！ -什麼？
You never went to school, right?
妳從來沒有上過學吧？
Shall we solve another problem?
我們再做一道題怎麼樣？
"There are 40 male and female employees at the bakery.
“麵包店有四十名男工和女工
How many men work at the bakery this year?"
今年麵包店有多少男工？”
Eighteen.
十八個
Correct. "How long did it take Yeong-hui to get to the bakery?"
正確 “永惠走到麵包店用了多少時間？”
-Thirty-two minutes. -Correct!
-三十二分鐘 -正確！
Wow!
天哪！
-You have an aptitude for math. -She's a genius.
-妳有學習數學的天賦喔 -她是天才
Ms. Sunwoo. I think the light's are going out.
鮮于老師，燈快要熄滅了
Then let's call it a day, and have some drinks instead?
那今天的課就上到這裡 我們一起喝酒吧？
-Yes!
-好！
-Juk Hyang, time for bed. -Okay.
-竹香，妳該睡覺了 -好
Cheers!
乾杯！
-Uh-oh. -Huh?
-喔 -啊？
-It's a blackout. -Here we go again.
-燈不亮了 -又來了
It does this everyday.
每天都這樣
-Drink this too. -No, you have it.
-這杯也喝掉吧 -不用，妳喝吧
-That's your loss. -Oh.
-那是妳的損失 -哦
Thank you, Apricot.
謝謝妳，杏子
The corner game is best for blackouts, right?
不開燈的時候 最適合玩四角遊戲，對不對？
What's a corner game?
四角遊戲是什麼？
It's a game of call. To a ghost living in corners.
是一種招鬼遊戲 可以招來住在角落裡的鬼
She thinks the ghost will tell her about her future husband.
她覺得鬼能告訴她 未來的丈夫是什麼人
-It sounds fun. -Shall we give it a try? Let's do it!
-聽起來很有趣 -要試試嗎？一起玩吧！
First, say your name out loud to tell it that you're playing the game.
首先，大聲講出妳的名字 讓鬼知道妳在玩這個遊戲
Then, say it backwards to end it.
遊戲結束時，倒著講出妳的名字
To start, you say Eun-ho. To end, you say Ho-eun.
開始的時候說“恩好” 結束的時候說“好恩”
When the person behind you taps your back, you move to the next corner.
妳後面的人拍妳後背的時候 妳就要去下一個角落
So we're just going around in circles? It sounds boring.
就是一直轉圈圈嗎？聽起來很無聊
We'll continue until someone doesn't move, because that will be the ghost.
我們要一直轉到有人不動才結束 因為那個人就是鬼
The most important thing.
最重要的是
Don't ever talk, while playing the game.
遊戲過程中不能講話
Let's begin. Azulea!
開始吧，金花！
Eun-ho.
恩好
-Apricot. -Orchid.
-杏子 -蘭草
What's this?
這是什麼？
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
Four.
四
Five?
五？
There are five people in the room.
這個房間裡有五個人
Can't we just stop now?
不能現在結束嗎？
I'm scared.
我害怕
It wasn't me! There's someone else in this room!
不是我！這個房間裡還有一個人！
Turn the light on!
點蠟燭！
-Huh? -Ms. Sunwoo?
-啊？ -鮮于老師？
-Ms. Sunwoo! -She disappeared.
-鮮于老師！ -她消失了
She's gone!
她不見了！
Hong-joo, do you remember when Yeon fell in the toilet?
紅朱，妳還記得阿硯掉進茅廁嗎？
Geez, that's out of the blue!
天哪，幹嘛突然問這個！
Of course, I remember. We were playing hide-and-seek blindfolded.
當然記得 當時我們蒙著眼睛玩捉迷藏遊戲
You pulled him out, Moo-yeong.
還是無影你拉他上來的
Nothing could make you cry, but you wept through the night.
一個從來都不哭的人哭了一整夜
Gosh, you pricks. Stop laughing at someone's painful past.
你們這些混帳 不要笑話別人的痛苦經歷了
I've become a germaphobe since that day, okay?
我從那天開始 變得有潔癖了，知道嗎？
Damn.
真是的
What happened to Black bear?
黑熊怎麼樣了？
He was so tactless and quiet, I thought he'd never be a mountain god.
他不夠圓滑、沉默寡言 我還以為他永遠做不上山神呢
He part-times at a folk village in the futur--
他在一個民俗村做兼職，是在未…
-He's working. -What "village"?
-他在工作啦 -什麼村？
"Part" what?
兼什麼？
By the way, it's a strange feeling.
話說回來，這種感覺真奇怪
Who would've thought us three would be drinking together?
誰能想到我們三個會一起喝酒呢？
In the year 1938, at that.
而且是在1938年
Ages ago, I made a wish.
很久以前，我許過一個願望
That time would just stop.
我希望時間可以停下來
That nothing would ever be taken from the three of us.
希望我們三個不會失去任何東西
But my wishes never come true.
但是我的願望從來不會實現
Damn it.
該死
Darn, I'm out of spirits.
見鬼，我的酒沒了
I'll make that wish come true. I'll be right back.
我會讓妳的願望成真的，我去去就回
Boo!
哇！
How did you live in the future world?
你在未來世界過得好嗎？
I watched Yeon.
我觀察過阿硯
In that era, he has so much.
他在那個時代擁有太多的東西
Working for Taluipa, with his family and friends at his side.
為奪衣婆效力 家人和朋友都陪在身邊
And even the woman he loves.
甚至還有他心愛的那個女人
Goodness.
天哪
-Tell me about you, not Yeon. -Me?
-不要講阿硯了，講講你吧 -我？
…has excellent thermal conductivity and look how sturdy it is.
…具有出色的導熱性，看它多結實
-All three types-- -…just like a brand new knife.
-三種類型都… -…就像一把新刀
Brother!
哥哥！
-You're literally designing a fight scene. -That's right.
-你在設計一個打鬥場景 -沒錯
As in this is a good place to fight--
這是一個適合打鬥的地方…
Now, that blunt blade is--
現在，那把鈍刀…
I am…
我…
living…
過得…
I'm living so, so, so good!
我過得太太太好了！
That's good to hear.
那就好
Apricot? Orchid? Where did you all go?
杏子？蘭草？妳們都去哪裡了？
Where is everyone?
大家都在哪裡？
Apricot!
杏子！
Excuse me.
不好意思
They're dead.
都死了
Hello? Hello? Anyone there?
有人嗎？外面有人嗎？
Hello?
有人嗎？
I'm in here! Hello?
我在裡面！有人嗎？
Is anyone out there? Hello?
外面有人嗎？有人嗎？
-Do you know what you've done? -We're sorry.
-妳們知不知道妳們做了什麼？ -對不起
We only did it for fun.
我們只是為了好玩
What? Fun?
什麼？好玩？
That game calls for the worst kinds of demons!
那個遊戲會招來最邪惡的妖怪！
We really didn't know.
我們真的不知道
What happened to Ms. Sunwoo?
鮮于老師怎麼了？
I'll take care of it. Go discipline yourselves in your room.
我會處理的，各自回房間思過吧
Oh, dear. Go along.
天哪，快去吧
I can never understand why humans continue to create such vile games.
我永遠無法理解 人類不停發明這種邪惡遊戲的原因
Corner games or ouija boards. They can't even handle it.
比如四角遊戲和通靈板 他們根本應付不了
Curiosity for what lies beyond.
都是出於對死後世界的好奇心
Gosh, I'm so pissed.
天哪，氣死我了
How dare some damn ghost show its face in my area!
該死的鬼竟敢在我的地盤上露面！
Wouldn't it be a residual ghost living in corners or thresholds?
應該是 殘留在角落或門檻的鬼吧？
It must be a twisted one, but I doubt it's a powerful one.
牠心理一定很扭曲 但我懷疑實力能有多強
I've never seen one take a human.
我從沒見過鬼劫持人類的情況
Let's catch it and ask "Why did you take her?"
我們抓牠過來問一下 “你為什麼劫持她？”
-Geez, it's so bothersome. -Gosh.
-天哪，傷腦筋 -真是的
Slow down. Stop being so impetuous.
慢一點，不要太衝動啦
It's here.
牠來了
But…
但是
Why did it take a human?
牠為什麼要劫持人類呢？
Hello? Anyone out there?
有人嗎？有人在外面嗎？
-You want to play the corner game? -You want to save Sunwoo Eun-ho, no?
-你要玩四角遊戲？ -你究竟想不想救回鮮于恩好？
-We need one for each corner. -Gosh, I'm really afraid of ghosts.
-每個角落都要站一個人 -天哪，我真的很怕鬼
Don't be so rude in front of us three mountain gods.
不要在我們三位山神面前放肆
You think we became gods playing golf at Baekdudaegan?
你以為我們在白頭大幹山上 打打高爾夫就能做上山神嗎？
Stay out of this, Hong-joo. We don't know what we're up against.
紅朱，妳不要參與了 我們還不清楚對方的實力
Thanks for your concern, but this is my home.
謝謝關心，但這裡是我的家
And I can protect myself.
而且我能保護我自己
You're not worried about me at all?
你一點都不擔心我嗎？
Just start.
開始吧
Show yourself and I'll slice you, ghost.
鬼，出來吧，我要剁了你
Everyone get in position. Don't talk until it comes out.
大家站好位置 在牠出現之前不要講話
-Yeah, yeah. -Especially the one behind me.
-知道了 -尤其是我身後這位
Kids, let's hurry and get this over with,
孩子們，快點辦完這件事
-so we can get more drinks. -Sure, sure.
-才能繼續喝酒啊 -知道了
Let's start by saying our names.
先喊出自己的名字吧
Koo Shin-ju.
具申炷
-Cheon Moo-yeong. -Lee Yeon.
-千無影 -李硯
Ryu Hong-joo.
柳紅朱
Where do you think Eun-ho disappeared to?
妳們說恩好消失到哪裡去了？
It's not our first time playing it. So, why did this happen?
我們不是第一次玩這個遊戲了 怎麼會這樣呢？
Gosh, I have goosebumps! Let's sprinkle salt first.
天哪，我起雞皮疙瘩了！ 先撒鹽驅邪吧
Apricot.
杏子
I'll go get it.
我去拿鹽
Guys, open the door.
姑娘們，開門
-Just come in. -My hands are full.
-妳直接進來吧 -我手上端著東西
Gosh, did she bring a whole sack of salt?
天哪，她是扛了一整袋鹽嗎？
-What? -I don't think that's her.
-幹嘛？ -好像不是她
-What do you mean? -Come on, guys.
-什麼意思？ -妳們快點
Open up. Hurry.
開門，快點
-That's not Apricot. -Huh?
-那不是杏子 -啊？
What? No way.
什麼？不可能
Blood, blood!
血，有血！
Wait a minute. Did we say our names backwards earlier?
等等，我們之前有沒有 倒著喊自己的名字？
-I forgot to do that! -What do we do?
-我忘了！ -怎麼辦？
The corner game isn't over yet!
四角遊戲還沒有結束呢！
It's here!
牠來了！
What're you doing with the lights off?
你們關著燈做什麼？
-Rang, is that you? -What are you doing still up?
-阿朗，是你嗎？ -你為什麼還不睡覺？
-Hey, turn the light on. -That's not your brother!
-開燈吧 -那不是你弟弟！
-Is it the ghost? -Yeah, I'm certain.
-是鬼嗎？ -是，我很肯定
Strike him, Lee Yeon. Hurry!
砍過去，李硯，快點！
No!
不要！
Geez.
天哪
-Rang! -You crazy bastard!
-阿朗！ -你這個瘋子！
Sorry.
對不起
Sorry, I thought you were the ghost.
對不起，我以為你是鬼
-Hey, Moo-yeong! You said-- -Said what?
-千無影！你明明說… -說什麼？
You said it was the ghost.
你說那是鬼啊
I haven't said a word since we started.
我們開始遊戲後，我一個字都沒講過
What?
什麼？
-You sure it wasn't you? -Why do you think it was me?
-真的不是你講的？ -你為什麼認為是我？
I'm sorry to interrupt.
抱歉打斷你們
But where did Madame Ryu go?
但是柳閣長去哪裡了？
Apricot! Did you see anything outside? A little while ago…
杏子！妳有在外面看到什麼嗎？ 就是剛剛…
I didn't see anything.
我什麼都沒看到
Open it.
打開
Gosh, I'm so scared.
天哪，我好怕
No. This isn't what I wanted.
不對，這不是我想要的結果
Hong-joo…
紅朱…
Hey, Cheon Moo-yeong! Moo-yeong!
千無影！無影！
Look at this. The salt has turned black.
你看，鹽變黑了
We were mistaken. It's no ordinary ghost.
我們弄錯了，這不是普通鬼
If it can take Hong-joo, it's a demon. One that's lived much longer than us.
既然可以抓走紅朱，牠一定是妖怪 比我們年齡大得多的妖怪
All of you. Don't step out of here until the rooster crows.
公雞啼叫前，妳們幾個不要出來
-Oh, no. -I'm scared.
-不會吧 -我害怕
My goodness.
真是的
-You're back. -I found a witness.
-你回來了 -我找到一位目擊者
-A cat? -Yeah, it's Shin-ju's specialty.
-是隻貓？ -沒錯，這是申炷的專長
What's it saying?
牠在說什麼？
It came in hidden among the new gisaengs.
那東西是混在新一批妓生裡進來的
Wearing old sandals.
穿著一雙舊草鞋
-What is it?
-牠是什麼東西？
What?
什麼？
Why?
怎麼了？
-What? Tell me. -Jang San-beom.
-是什麼？告訴我 -萇山虎
Jang San-beom. No wonder it kept mimicking voices.
萇山虎，難怪那東西總是模仿人講話
-He's quite a big shot, no? -She hasn't got much time.
-他很厲害吧？ -紅朱的時間不多了
-And we know nothing about him. -Let's find a way to catch him first.
-而我們對他一無所知 -先想辦法抓到他吧
Let's do that.
就這麼辦
Jang San-beom?
萇山虎？
Hey, Rang.
喂，阿朗
-Let me borrow your guys, huh? -Not a chance.
-把你的手下借給我吧？ -做夢
I'll buy you 10 bowls of naengmyeon.
我請你吃十碗冷麵
I already had some.
我已經吃過了
Hey, just--
喂，你就…
What is it you want? Just tell me.
你想要什麼？儘管告訴我
-Get me your friend's blood. -Are you a damn mosquito?
-我要你朋友的血 -你是該死的蚊子嗎？
-Forget it, then. -No, no, no. Fine.
-不給算了 -別這樣，好吧
I'll try talking to him.
我去找他談談
Boss!
老大！
Hey, I told you not to do that when you make an entrance.
我有講過，不要在出現的時候翻跟斗
I'll fix it, sir!
遵命，下次改正！
But what did you summon me for, boss?
老大，你叫我來有事嗎？
You…
你…
-You'd like to break the deal? -Jang San-beom has…
-你想毀約？ -萇山虎…
-taken the mountain god of the west. -What?
-抓走了西邊山神 -什麼？
So what? Didn't you ask for it?
那又如何？不是你求著我要的嗎？
I can't have it take her.
我不能讓牠帶走紅朱
-Hong-joo. -I pity your situation,
-紅朱 -我同情你的處境
but a deal with a god is non-refundable.
但是與神達成的約定不可撤回
Just-- Just tell me the way!
為我指條明路吧！
-Where should I go? Please-- -The Path of the Damned.
-我應該去哪裡？求求你… -詛咒之路
It's somewhere even Taluipa can't peek into!
那是連奪衣婆都不敢窺探的地方！
Don't go!
不要去！
Don't do anything.
什麼都不要做
How come? Huh?
為什麼？啊？
I see endless darkness in your eyes.
我看得出你眼中有無盡的黑暗
Guys like you are perfect prey for a world like that.
你這樣的人是那裡的完美獵物
I will return alive at all costs.
我會不惜一切代價活著回來的
With Hong-joo safe by me.
把紅朱平安地帶回來
What a fool.
真是個傻瓜
She's the sole person who returned alive from Jang San-beom's grasp.
她是唯一一個 從萇山虎手中活著回來的人
Granny, you were caught by Jang San-beom?
婆婆，妳被萇山虎抓走過？
My sisters, just the four of us.
我們姊妹，一共四個人
It was the winter solstice.
那天是冬至
The night grew long, so we played the corner game and--
冬夜漫漫，我們玩起了四角遊戲…
Yes. Cut to the chase.
好了，直接講重點
Well, I talked out loud.
我不小心
By mistake.
大聲講話了
So where did he take you?
那他把妳抓去哪裡了？
-I couldn't see because it was so dark. -Are you kidding me.
-太黑了，沒看清楚 -開什麼玩笑
Aside from me, many maidens were taken by him.
除我之外，很多少女也被他抓走了
-Maidens? -Yeah.
-少女？ -嗯
I hear they're all his wives.
聽說她們都是他的妻子
So that's why he only takes women, huh?
難怪他只抓女人
If he searches for maidens, why did he take you?
既然目標是少女 他為什麼要抓妳呢？
In the olden days, I was the beauty of this village.
想當年，我可是這座村裡的美人啊
When I went out to work in the fields,
當我去田裡幹活時
the bachelors all over town would drool.
全鎮的單身漢都會流口水
Hey, stop, stop.
別說了
-What's wrong with her? -I hear her mind comes and goes.
-她怎麼回事？ -聽說她時而清醒，時而糊塗
So how did you return alive?
妳是怎麼活著回來的？
-I followed Ttotto. -Ttotto? What's a "Ttotto"?
-跟著圖圖 -圖圖？“圖圖”是什麼？
So what I'm saying is-- Well, that's--
我的意思是…那就是…
-I don't remember. -Gosh. Damn it.
-我忘了 -天哪，真是的
-Did you get to see Jang San-beom? -I-- I did.
-妳有看到萇山虎的長相嗎？ -有啊
-I saw him. -What did he look like?
-我看到他了 -他長什麼樣子？
-I need paper and a brush. -Paper and brush, go.
-我需要紙和筆 -準備紙和筆，快
What? Is that all?
什麼？畫好了？
Is this a butt?
這是屁股嗎？
This. What's this?
這個，這個是什麼？
-Our Ttotto. -This is Ttotto?
-我們圖圖 -這就是圖圖？
A stray cat gave birth to Ttotto in front of my house.
一隻流浪貓在我家門前生下了圖圖
It would follow me everywhere.
牠常常跟著我走來走去
A cat?
是隻貓？
-Hey. -Gosh, its claws hurt.
-喂 -哎呀，牠爪子撓得我好痛
It was holding onto the warm fireplace for dear life--
牠緊緊抓著溫暖的壁爐不放…
-Why the cat? -Cats are creatures that can see ghosts.
-抱隻貓來做什麼？ -貓這種動物能看到鬼
This one will pave the way to that world.
這隻貓可以打前陣 帶我們進入那個世界
This is a weapon.
這是武器
Made of wood grown on human blood and flesh.
是用人類血肉上長出的樹木做成的
Wow, there's nothing better to catch old demons like Jang San-beom.
沒有比這更適合去抓 萇山虎那種老妖怪的武器了
The duduri tree? How did you find this?
豆豆里樹？你怎麼找到這個的？
DUDURI- TREE GROWN ON HUMAN BLOOD AND FLESH
（豆豆里樹 生長在人類血肉上的樹）
Paid a hefty sum.
我付了一大筆錢
Great, we're all ready then.
太好了，那我們就準備好了
Now, all we have to do is wait for the sun to set.
等太陽下山便可以行動了
I'm counting on you.
就靠你了
If you go in, you might not get out. Just send your friend.
如果你進去，可能會出不來 還是讓你朋友去吧
-I have to go. -I mean, why?
-我必須要去 -為什麼？
Hong-joo would've done the same for me.
換作紅朱，她也會進去救我的
Then take me, not Cheon Moo-yeong.
那你帶我去，不要帶千無影
I can go with anyone, but you! How could I send you to your death!
我帶誰去都可以，只有你不行！ 我怎麼可以讓你去送死！
Do you trust him?
你信得過他嗎？
An old friend or whatnot. That was centuries ago.
老朋友什麼的都是幾百年前的事情了
Ironically though, as soon as I met Moo-yeong,
諷刺的是，我剛見到無影
Jang San-beom showed up.
萇山虎便出現了
Even when playing the corner game, he wanted to leave Hong-joo out.
甚至在玩四角遊戲時 他也有勸紅朱退出
You mean…
你是說
He brought Jang San-beom?
萇山虎是他帶來的？
I'm not sure. I still want to trust him.
還不能確定，我依然想相信他
How pathetic.
不可救藥
What if this is a trap?
如果這是個陷阱呢？
At least, we'll know why Moo-yeong came to see me.
我們至少會知道無影來見我的原因
-Go tell Taluipa about this. -That you're off to catch Jang San-beom?
-你去告訴奪衣婆吧 -你們去抓萇山虎的事情嗎？
It's a place her eyes can't reach. She's old, so she might worry.
那是她眼睛看不到的地方 她年紀大了，可能會擔心
Please be careful. And please save Eun-ho too.
拜託你小心一點，也請你救出恩好
Okay. Take good care of Rang and the others.
知道了，好好照顧阿朗和其他人
-We'll start at eight o'clock sharp. -Okay.
-我們八點整開始行動 -好
Hey, tie it.
綁在手上
Is this my way back?
這是我回來的路嗎？
Just in case.
以防萬一
-Thanks for worrying about me. -Don't ever die.
-謝謝你關心我 -別死掉
You know if you die there, you can't even save your soul, right?
你也知道死在那裡的人 靈魂是無法得救的吧？
Let's go.
走吧
I'll buy you naengmyeon when I'm back.
等我回來請你吃冷麵
Hey.
喂
Hey!
喂！
Gwanghwamun?
光化門？
-What? We're in the Joseon Dynasty period? -Whenever this is, we find Hong-joo first.
-什麼？這是朝鮮王朝時代嗎？ -不管了，先去找紅朱
Geez, seriously.
真是的
Gosh, where the hell do we find her?
天哪，我們要去哪裡找她啊？
-Hey, hold on. Isn't it a little strange? -What is?
-等等，這不是有點奇怪嗎？ -什麼？
There's not a single person, let alone any sound.
一個人都沒有，更別提聲音了
Hong-joo!
紅朱！
Ryu Hong-joo!
柳紅朱！
This won't do. Let's split up and look.
這樣不行，我們分頭去找吧
Hey, Moo-yeong! Cheon Moo-yeong!
無影！千無影！
-Are they all human? -Yeah.
-都是人類嗎？ -是的
How long do you think they've been dead?
依你看，他們死亡多久了？
-At least, three days. -Geez.
-至少三天了 -天哪
Who's that?
那是誰？
Who are you? Answer me.
妳是誰？回答我
Who did this?
這是誰幹的？
Jang San-beom.
萇山虎
Do you know where he is?
妳知道他在哪裡嗎？
Where is he?
他在哪？
Tell me. We'll catch him.
告訴我，我們會抓住他的
Want to get out of here?
妳想離開這裡嗎？
Can you take us to Jang San-beom?
妳能帶我們去找萇山虎嗎？
-What the? -Where did she go?
-搞什麼？ -她去哪裡了？
Moo-yeong, no! Don't breathe!
無影，不對！不要呼吸！
What's this? Hey!
這是什麼？哎呀！
-Hey, Moo-yeong! -I can't untie the ropes!
-無影！ -我解不開繩子！
Oh, gosh.
真是的
No, no, no! Go away, go!
別過來！走開！
Ladies, no. Let's talk it out, huh?
各位女士，別這樣，我們談談吧
Let's talk! Come on!
談談吧！拜託啦！
What?
什麼？
Hey, Moo-yeong!
無影！
We're not dead. What is this?
我們沒有死，這是什麼？
This is fake blood.
是假血
Goodness.
天哪
And cut! Okay!
停！好了！
-Let's get up. We'll resume in ten! -Huh?
-起來吧，十分鐘後繼續拍攝！ -啊？
Let's change for the next scene. Hurry!
換下一場戲的佈景吧，快點！
IN SUPPORT OF TV SHOW "JANG SAN-BEOM'S BRIDE"
（贊助電視節目《萇山虎的新娘》）
What the hell is this?
這究竟怎麼回事啊？
How is this possible?
這怎麼可能？
Once upon a time, there lived a tiger at Jangsan,
很久以前，萇山住著一隻老虎
that had a knack for imitating others.
有模仿別人的本領
This is the world you've created.
這是你創造的世界
So this stage was made from stealing my memories?
這個舞台是用我被盜的記憶搭建的？
-Why are they spinning? -I'm Kim Du-han.
-他們為什麼要轉圈？ -我是金斗漢
Gosh, I'm losing my mind!
天哪，我要瘋了！
One hour left. We must find Hong-joo in time.
還剩一小時，我們必須及時找到紅朱
Try to save this woman, if you can.
有本事就來救這個女人吧
I'm going to kill him.
我要殺了他
-I… -Cut the string!
-我… -砍斷繩子！
Why can't I let go of this?
我為什麼不捨得放手？
He intended for us to fight each other.
他是故意引我們互相鬥爭
TRANSLATED BY TIFFANY HWANG
字幕翻譯：鄒琳